GEORGE EFTICHIOU

CONTACT INFORMATION



+357 96452718



eftichiou@hotmail.com



https://www.geef.cc

EDUCATION

Self-Taught Coding | 2019-2021

During this period, I've spent a significant amount of time learning primarily from Udemy, focusing on JavaScript, React, Node.js, Next.js, Java, and other web-related technologies.

Intercollege, Larnaca, Cyprus | 2009-2011 Computer Science Diploma Programming Courses:

- Programming Courses:Visual Basic Programming
- C++ Programming
- Pascal Programming
- Cobol Programming
- Assembly Programming
- Database Creation and Analysis
- Information Analysis

Agios Georgios High School, Larnaca, Cyprus | 2004-2006 Computer Science

Technologies Exposed To:

- Javascript (Typescript)
- ReactJS & NextJS
- NodeJS
- Redux
- CSS (SASS & Styled Components & Modules)
- Webpack
- Websockets (Socket.io & Netty)
- Rest APIs
- Nginx
- Bash
- Docker
- Kubernetes & OpenShift
- Git & Jira & Jenkins
- MongoDB
- SQL & Hibernate
- Java (Spring)AWS (Lightsail)

React Native (Not in Corporate level)
Rust (Not in Corporate level)

- Rust - Scala (Not in Corporate level) (Not in Corporate level)

(Not in Corporate level)

(Not in Corporate level)

Languages

- Greek (Native)
- English (Fluent)
- Russian (Basic Communication)

Traits

- Learn Enthusiast
- Team Player
- Hard Working
- Multi-Tasking

References

Available on Request

PERSONAL PROFILE

Having worked extensively with backend and frontend applications coupled with my professional certifications I have gained exposure and established various technical skills relating to web developing. A proactive, self-motivated individual, with strong learning enthusiasm. I relish the opportunity to work as part of a team, enjoying the challenge of taking on new roles and responsibilities in dynamic working environments.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Developer

Amdocs, Limassol, Cyprus | 2022 - Today

Software Developer

Cypos Systems, Limassol, Cyprus | 2021 – 2022

Career Transition Self-Taught Coding | 2019 - 2021

Reception

Aeneas Hotel, Avia Napa, Cyprus | Mar - Nov2019

Reservations - Reception

Downtown Inn Kyoto, Kyoto, Japan | Dec 2018 - Feb 2019

Reservations - Reception

Europa Melbourne, Australia | Jul 2017 - Nov 2018

Reservations - Reception

Randwick Lodge, Sydney, Australia | Dec 2016 - May 2017

Projects & Contribution

- Amdocs-SRM a resource management system created in React & Redux for telecommunication companies.
- Amdocs-NEF (network expose function) a React & Redux program for telecommunication companies.
- Cypos Systems web application using ReactJS & NextJS Serverless Functions for API calls. The application was requested to be using an easy way of adding products to their wish list using files system and Markdown language.
- Ecommerce integrated with Stripe using NodeJS backend & React, NextJs frontend. Frontend running on Vercel, Backend running on AWS lightsail having the database on MongoAtlas. Experience gain project.
- Web application using netty (Socket.io) websocket implementation on Java SpringBoot which multiple users can be logged in on the frontend (NextJs) to synchronize their items in real time using app's UI and chat. The project is using SQL and Hibernate.
- Foody Delivery Platform (Cyprus) and ICG Solutions (Spain) integration that allows the POS software of ICG to communicate during online transaction made on Foody platform. The project is using Typescript on NodeJS (Express) server on AWS cluster implementing Nginx Load Balancing in case an instance goes down. The API bridge code uses asynchronous concurrency for API calls to use NodeJS asynchronous I/O non-blocking capabilities.
- Android Application that implements basic communication between a NodeJS server (listening to a file creation) so it can synchronize latest items between Android App and NodeJs server.